# NATE VOGEL

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Mobile: (810) 853-9203 Email: navogel@gmail.com

Address: 377 Athens Way, Nashville TN 37228

Development Portfolio: navogel.github.io/

**GitHub:** github.com/navogel **Dribbble:** dribbble.com/navogel

# SUMMARY

I'm a design-minded developer with a passion for coding & using technology to create amazing user experiences. I love helping projects go from inception to deployment.

My Story: After living and traveling abroad from 2013-2016, I came home to Nashville with a desire to help people travel smarter through technology. I hired a small team of developers and built my first app prototype, doing all the design, HTML, and CSS. I was hooked, and I knew my future lay with web development and design.

# SKILLSET

- · Single page application design, prototyping and wireframing.
- HTML5 and CSS3 with Flexbox
- · Vanilla Javascript & React
- Source control with Git, GitHub, and Bitbucket
- · Consuming external REST APIs
- · Sprint & Story management with Jira
- · Mapping: Mapbox API & Leaflet, geocoding
- · Material UI & Ant Design
- NPM, Webpack
- C#, ASP.net, SQL Server
- Deployment: Azure, Firebase, AWS.
- Adobe: Xd, Photoshop, Lightroom, Premier Pro, After Effects

# **DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS**

#### FRONT END CAPSTONE: TRIPBLAZR

After three months at NSS I was ready for my most ambitious personal project yet: an app that allows users to collaboratively create and plan trips anywhere in the world, and then become a "TripBlazr" by publishing them; allowing future travelers to follow in their footsteps.

- · Created ERD and data flow with mock API via JSON SERVER.
- · Designed layout wireframes with Xd.
- Utilized Mapbox API for custom tiles and geocoding.
- · Used React Framework with Material UI.
- Used React Leaflet to manage mapping components.
- Deployed the static app to Azure, and the API to Heroku.

# PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

# JUNIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | Aug 2019 - Present

6-month apprenticeship program focusing on full-stack development projects in a technical environment that includes: JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS3, Git, Github, npm, C#, ASP.net, and SQL Server.

- Created single-page applications using both vanilla Javascript and React
- Consumed external APIs and built out ERDs for data architecture with a REST API via JSON Server.
- · Utilized Flexbox, Grid for UX/UI layout & styling.
- Team based projects with agile sprints, pair-programming, issue tracking, stories, and retrospectives.
- · Gained experience with source and version control with Git and Github.

# SEENASH.COM FOUNDER / PRODUCT MANAGER

Tech Startup | Oct 2017 - Present

Founder of a Nashville startup that brought a tourism-focused single page web application from concept to deployment, in partnership with the Nashville Convention and Visitors Corp & www.VisitMusicCity.com.

- Created a first-of-its-kind video mapping platform with both mobile and desktop applications.
- Managed a team of 2 developers through prototyping stages to a deployed MVP.
- UX/UI: product design, wireframing, and application HTML/CSS
- Feature development, product road maps, and sprint planning.
- Facilitated strategic partnerships with the NCVC & Premier Parking.

Technical Environment: Javascript / Git / Angular & Ionic Frameworks / Jira / BitBucket / AWS / Mapbox / Google Maps & Places API

## FREELANCE DIGITAL MEDIA

www.nathanvogelphography.com | May 2010 - Oct 2017

Wedding & Event Photography, Videography. Tools: Photoshop, After Effects, Premiere Pro. Getty / IStock Travel Photographer. Website design.

#### **TECHNICAL RECRUITER**

Otterbase / AllTech | Aug 2007 - May 2010

Agency recruiter responsible for filling contract, contract-to-hire, and permanent tech positions in Nashville TN.

- Sourcing, interviewing, tech screening, on-boarding.
- Top Recruiter by placements and revenue in every guarter worked.

## **EDUCATION**

# **NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL**

Apprentice Software Developer 2019-2020

## **CEDARVILLE UNIVERSITY**

B.A. Marketing